I was three months pregnant with twins
كنت حامل في توأم في الشهر الثالث
when my husband Ross and I went to my second sonogram.
عندما ذهبت وزوجي روس إلى فحص الموجات الصوتية الثاني لي
I was 35 years old at the time,
حينها، كنت في ال 35 من عمري
and I knew that that meant we had a higher risk
وعلمت أنه لدينا نسبة مخاطرة مرتفعة
of having a child with a birth defect.
أن ننجب طفلًا بعيب خلقي
So, Ross and I researched the standard birth defects,
لذلك، بحثت أنا وروس عن العيوب الخلقية
and we felt reasonably prepared.
وشعرنا باستعداد معقول
Well, nothing would have prepared us
حسنًا، لا شيء كان قد سيعدّنا
for the bizarre diagnosis that we were about to face.
للتشخيص الغريب الذي كنّا على وشك مواجهته
The doctor explained that one of our twins, Thomas,
شرح الدكتور أن واحدًا من التوأمين، توماس،
had a fatal birth defect called anencephaly.
كان لديه عيب خلقي مميت يُدعى انعدام الدماغ
This means that his brain was not formed correctly
هذا يعني أن مخه لم يكن قد تكوّن بشكل صحيح
because part of his skull was missing.
لأن جزءً من جمجمته كان مفقودًا
Babies with this diagnosis typically die in utero
عادةً يموت أطفال هذا المرض في الرحم
or within a few minutes, hours or days of being born.
أو خلال دقائق أو ساعات أو أيام من ولادتهم
But the other twin, Callum,
لكن التوأم الأخ، كالوم،
appeared to be healthy, as far as the doctor could tell,
بدا أنه معافى، بقدر ما أمكن الطبيب أن يقول
and these twins were identical,
وهذان التوأمان كانا متماثلين،
genetically identical.
متطابقين وراثيًا
So after a lot of questions about how this could have possibly happened,
بعد الكثير من الأسئلة عن كيف أنه أمكن حدوث ذلك
a selective reduction was mentioned,
تم إخباري باختزال إختياري للتوأم المصاب
and while this procedure was not impossible,
في حين أن العملية لم تكن مستحيلة
it posed some unique risks for the healthy twin and for me,
كان يوجد بعض المخاطر على الجنين السليم وعليّ
so we decided to carry the pregnancy to term.
لذلك قررنا أن نكمل الحمل لنهايته
So there I was, three months pregnant, with two trimesters ahead of me,
كنت حامل في الشهر الثالث، وبقي ثلثين آخرين
and I had to find a way to manage my blood pressure and my stress.
وكان يجب أن أتحكم جيدًا في ضغط دمي وتوتري
And it felt like having a roommate point a loaded gun at you for six months.
شعرت وكأن لدي رفيق يوجه بندقية لي ستة أشهر
But I stared down the barrel of that gun for so long
لكني حدّقت لأسفل هذه البندقية مدة طويلة
that I saw a light at the end of the tunnel.
حتّى رأيت ضوء في نهاية النفق
While there was nothing we could do to prevent the tragedy,
في حين أنه لا يمكننا فعل شيء لمنع الفاجعة
I wanted to find a way for Thomas's brief life
أنا أردت أن أجد طريقًا لحياة توماس القصيرة
to have some kind of positive impact.
ليكون لديه نوع من التأثير الإيجابي
So I asked my nurse about organ, eye and tissue donation.
لذلك سألت ممرضتي عن تبرع الأعضاء والأنسجة
She connected with our local organ-procurement organization,
وهي تواصلت مع منظمة شراء الأعضاء المحلية
the Washington Regional Transplant Community.
جمعية زرع الأعضاء الإقليمية بواشنطن
WRTC explained to me
WRTC شرحت لي أن توماس
that Thomas would probably be too small at birth to donate for transplant,
من المحتمل أن يولد صغير جدًا للتبرع بالزراعة
and I was shocked:
وأنا صُدِمت
I didn't even know you could be rejected for that.
لم أكُن أعرف حتى أنك من الممكن أن تُرفَض لذلك
But they said that he would be a good candidate to donate for research.
لكن قالوا أنه سيكون مرشح جيد للتبرع للأبحاث
This helped me see Thomas in a new light.
هذا ساعدني أن أرى توماس بشكل جديد
As opposed to just a victim of a disease,
بدلًا من مجرد ضحية لمرض،
I started to see him as a possible key to unlock a medical mystery.
بدأت في رؤيته كمفتاح محتمل لفتح لغزًا طبيًا
On March 23, 2010,
في 23 مارس 2010،
the twins were born, and they were both born alive.
وُلِد التوأم، كلاهما أحياء
And just like the doctor said,
وفقط كما قال الدكتور،
Thomas was missing the top part of his skull,
كان توماس بدون الجزء العلوي من جمجمته،
but he could nurse,
لكن كان يستطيع أن يرضع
drink from a bottle,
ويشرب من زجاجة،
cuddle and grab our fingers like a normal baby,
يعانق ويمسك أصابعنا مثل أي طفل طبيعي،
and he slept in our arms.
وكان ينام بين أذرعنا
After six days, Thomas died in Ross's arms
بعد ستة أيام، مات توماس بين ذراعيّ روس
surrounded by our family.
محاطًا بعائلتنا
We called WRTC, who sent a van to our home
اتصلنا ب WRTC، وأرسلوا عربة إلى منزلنا
and brought him to Children's National Medical Center.
وأحضروه إلى المركز الوطني الطبي للأطفال
A few hours later, we got a call to say that the recovery was a success,
بعد ساعات،اتصلوا وقالوا أن الانتعاش كان ناجحًا
and Thomas's donations would be going to four different places.
وتبرعات توماس سوف تذهب إلى أربع جهات مختلفة
His cord blood would go to Duke University.
دم حبله السري سوف يذهب إلى جامعة ديوك
His liver would go to a cell-therapy company called Cytonet in Durham.
وكَبدُه سيذهب إلى شركة علاج خلايا في دورهام
His corneas would go to Schepens Eye Research Institute,
وقرنيته ستذهب إلى معهد تشيبنس لأبحاث العيون،
which is part of Harvard Medical School,
وهو جزء من كلية الطب بجامعة هارفارد،
and his retinas would go to the University of Pennsylvania.
وشبكية العين ستذهب إلى جامعة بنسلفانيا
A few days later, we had a funeral with our immediate family,
بعد بضعة أيام،أقمنا جنازة مع عائلتنا الحالية
including baby Callum,
بما في ذلك الطفل كالوم،
and we basically closed this chapter in our lives.
ونحن أساسًا أغلقنا هذا الفصل من حياتنا
But I did find myself wondering, what's happening now?
ولكني وجدت نفسي أتساءل ما الذي يحدث الآن؟
What are the researchers learning?
ما الذّي تُعلّمه الأبحاث؟
And was it even worthwhile to donate?
هل كانت تستحق عناء التبرع؟
WRTC invited Ross and I to a grief retreat,
WRTC دَعتني وروس إلى جلسة لاعتزال الحزن
and we met about 15 other grieving families
وقابلنا حوالي 15 أسرة مكلومة أخرى
who had donated their loved one's organs for transplant.
الذين قد تبرعوا بأعضاء أحبابهم للزراعة
Some of them had even received letters
حتى بعضهم قد تلقّى خطابات
from the people who received their loved one's organs,
من الذين حصلوا على أعضاء أحبابهم،
saying thank you.
ليقولوا لهم شكرًا لكم
I learned that they could even meet each other
وتعلمت أنهم حتى من الممكن أن يتقابلوا
if they'd both sign a waiver,
إذا كان كلاهما وقعا على تنازل،
almost like an open adoption.
تقريبًا كاعتماد مفتوح.
And I was so excited, I thought maybe I could write a letter
وكنت متشوقة، اعتقدت أنه يمكنني كتابة خطاب
or I could get a letter and learn about what happened.
أو بإمكاني تلقي خطاب وافهم عن الذي حدث،
But I was disappointed to learn
ولكن خاب أملي لأفهم
that this process only exists for people who donate for transplant.
هذه العملية متاحة فقط للّذين تبرعوا للزراعة
So I was jealous. I had transplant envy, I guess.
لذلك شعُرت بالغيرة، لقد زرعت الحسد، أعتقد
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
But over the years that followed,
لكن على مدار السنوات التي تلت ذلك،
I learned a lot more about donation,
تعلّمت الكثير عن التبرع،
and I even got a job in the field.
وحتى أنني حصلت على وظيفة في هذا المجال.
And I came up with an idea.
وخطرت لي فكرة.
I wrote a letter that started out,
كتبت خطاب الذي بدأ بـ ،
"Dear Researcher."
"عزيزي الباحث."
I explained who I was,
شرحت من أكون،
and I asked if they could tell me why they requested infant retinas
وطلبت إخباري لماذا طلبوا شبكية عين الرضيع
in March of 2010,
في مارس 2010،
and I asked if my family could visit their lab.
وسألت إذا كان بإمكان عائلتي زيارة مختبرهم
I emailed it to the eye bank that arranged the donation,
أرسلت الإيميل إلى بنك العين الذي رتب التبرع
the Old Dominion Eye Foundation,
مؤسسة أولد دومينيون العين،
and asked if they could send it to the right person.
وسألت إذا استطاعوا إرساله للشخص الصحيح.
They said that they had never done this before,
قالوا أنهم لم يفعلوا ذلك من قبل،
and they couldn't guarantee a response,
وأنهم لا يضمنون أن نحصل على رد
but they wouldn't be an obstacle, and they would deliver it.
ولكنهم لن يكونوا عقبة، وسوف يرسلوه.
Two days later, I got a response
بعد مرور يومين، حصلت على رد
from Dr. Arupa Ganguly of the University of Pennsylvania.
من د/أروبا جانجولي من جامعة ولاية بنسلفانيا
She thanked me for the donation,
شكرتني على التبرع،
and she explained that she is studying retinoblastoma,
وشرحت لي أنها تدرس ورم الشبكية
which is a deadly cancer of the retina
وهو سرطان قاتل للشبكية
that affects children under the age of five,
يصيب الأطفال في عمر أقل من 5 سنوات
and she said that yes, we were invited to visit her lab.
وقالت نعم، ودَعتنا لزيارة مختبرها
So next we talked on the phone,
وبعد ذلك تحدثنا على الهاتف
and one of the first things she said to me
وأول شيء قالته لي كان
was that she couldn't possibly imagine how we felt,
أنها ربما لا يمكن أن تتخيل كيف كان شعورنا
and that Thomas had given the ultimate sacrifice,
وأن توماس قد أعطى التضحية الكبرى
and that she seemed to feel indebted to us.
وبدت أنها تشعر أنها مديونة لنا
So I said, "Nothing against your study,
فقلت "لا شيء ضد دراستك"،
but we didn't actually pick it.
لكن فعليّا نحن لم نختره
We donated to the system, and the system chose your study.
نحن تبرعنا للمنظومة والمنظومة اختارت دراستك
I said, "And second of all, bad things happen to children every day,
ثانيًا، الأشياء السيئة تحدث للأطفال كل يوم
and if you didn't want these retinas,
وإذا لم تريدي هذه الشبكية،
they would probably be buried in the ground right now.
لكانت على الأرجح مدفونة في الأرض الآن
So to be able to participate in your study
لذلك وحتى تستطيعي المساهمة في دراستك
gives Thomas's life a new layer of meaning.
أعطي لحياة توماس معنى جديد
So, never feel guilty about using this tissue."
لذلك لا تشعري بالذنب أبدًا على استخدام شبكيته
Next, she explained to me how rare it was.
بعد ذلك، شرحَت لي كيف أن هذا نادرالحدوث
She had placed a request for this tissue six years earlier
وكانت قد طلبت هذا النسيج سابقًا من ست سنوات
with the National Disease Research Interchange.
مع المؤسسة الوطنية لتبادل بحوث الأمراض
She got only one sample of tissue that fit her criteria,
وحصلت فقط على عينة نسيج واحدة تناسب المعايير
and it was Thomas's.
وكانت لتوماس.
Next, we arranged a date for me to come visit the lab,
بعد ذلك، رتبنا موعد لي لزيارة المختبر
and we chose March 23, 2015, which was the twins' fifth birthday.
وكان23 مارس2015 وهو عيد ميلاد التوأم الخامس
After we hung up, I emailed her some pictures of Thomas and Callum,
بعد أن اغلقنا، أرسلت لها صور لتوماس وكالوم
and a few weeks later, we received this T-shirt in the mail.
وبعد عدة أسابيع، استلمنا هذا القميص بالبريد
A few months later, Ross, Callum and I piled in the car
بعد عدة أشهر، صعدنا أنا وتوماس وكالوم في السيارة
and we went for a road trip.
وذهبنا في رحلة على الطريق
We met Arupa and her staff,
قابلنا أروبا وموظفيها،
and Arupa said that when I told her not to feel guilty, that it was a relief,
وقالت أني أغثتها حين أخبرتها ألا تشعر بالذنب
and that she hadn't seen it from our perspective.
وأنها لم تكن تراها من وجهة نظرنا
She also explained that Thomas had a secret code name.
ووضحت أن توماس له اسم كـ رمز سري
The same way Henrietta Lacks is called HeLa,
بنفس الطريقة التي تُدعى بها هنريتا ليكس"هيلا"
Thomas was called RES 360.
فإن توماس يُدعى"RES 360"
RES means research,
RES اختصارًا لبحث
and 360 means he was the 360th specimen
و360 تعني أنه العينة رقم 360
over the course of about 10 years.
على مدى نحو 10 أعوام.
She also shared with us a unique document,
شاركت أيضا معنا وثيقة فريدة من نوعها،
and it was the shipping label
وكانت بطاقة شحن
that sent his retinas from DC to Philadelphia.
والتي أرسلت شبكيته من العاصمة إلى فيلادلفيا
This shipping label is like an heirloom to us now.
هذه البطاقة بمثابة أملاك موروثة لنا الآن
It's the same way that a military medal or a wedding certificate might be.
نفس طريقة الميدالية العسكرية وقسيمة الزواج
Arupa also explained that she is using Thomas's retina and his RNA
وشرحَت أنها تستخدم شبكيته والحمض الريبوزي
to try to inactivate the gene that causes tumor formation,
لتحاول تعطيل الجين المتسبب في تكوين الورم
and she even showed us some results that were based on RES 360.
وعرضت علينا النتائج التي اعتمدت على RES 360
Then she took us to the freezer
بعدها أخذتنا إلى حجرة التجميد
and she showed us the two samples that she still has
وعرضت علينا العينتين اللّتان ما زالا معها
that are still labeled RES 360.
واللّتان ما زالا باسم RES 360
There's two little ones left.
يوجد اثنتان صغيرتان متروكين
She said she saved it
قالت أنها حفظتهم
because she doesn't know when she might get more.
لأنها لا تعلم متى قد تحصل على أكثر من ذلك
After this, we went to the conference room
بعد ذلك، ذهبنا إلى غرفة المؤتمرات
and we relaxed and we had lunch together,
واسترخينا وتناولنا الغذاء معًا،
and the lab staff presented Callum with a birthday gift.
وأهدى موظفي المختبر كالوم هدية عيد ميلاده
It was a child's lab kit.
كانت أدوات مختبر خاصة بالأطفال
And they also offered him an internship.
وعرضوا عليه أيضًا فترة تدريب
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
So in closing, I have two simple messages today.
وفي الختام، فأنا لديّ رسالتين بسيطتين اليوم
One is that most of us probably don't think about donating to research.
الأولى:معظمنا ربما لايفكر في التبرع للأبحاث
I know I didn't. I think I'm a normal person.
أعلم أني لم أفكر. أعتقد أني إنسانة طبيعية
But I did it.
لكني فعلتها.
It was a good experience, and I recommend it,
كانت تجربة جيدة، وأوصي بها،
and it brought my family a lot of peace.
كما أنها أحضرت لعائلتي الكثير من السلام
And second is if you work with human tissue
وثانيًا، لو تعمل مع أنسجة الإنسان
and you wonder about the donor and about the family,
وتتسائل عن المتبرع وعن عائلته
write them a letter.
اكتب لهم خطابًا
Tell them you received it, tell them what you're working on,
أخبرهم أنك استلمتها، وأخبرهم ماذا تفعل بها
and invite them to visit your lab,
وادعِهم لزيارة مختبرك
because that visit may be even more gratifying for you
لأن هذه الزيارة قد تكون ممتعة لك
than it is for them.
أكثر منهم
And I'd also like to ask you a favor.
وأيضًا أود أن أطلب منك معروفًا
If you're ever successful in arranging one of these visits,
إذا نجحت من قبل في ترتيب زيارة كهذه،
please tell me about it.
من فضلك أخبرني عنها
The other part of my family's story
أما الجزء الآخر من قصة عائلتي
is that we ended up visiting all four facilities
هي أننا انتهينا من زيارة المرافق الأربعة
that received Thomas's donations.
التي أخذت تبرعات توماس
And we met amazing people doing inspiring work.
وقابلنا أشخاص مذهلة يقومون بعمل مُلهِم
The way I see it now is that Thomas got into Harvard,
الطريقة التي أراها بها الآن وكأن توماس حصل على جامعة هارفارد
Duke and Penn --
ديوك وبنسلفانيا
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
And he has a job at Cytonet,
ولديه وظيفة في سيتونت
and he has colleagues and he has coworkers
ولديه زملاء دراسة وزملاء عمل
who are in the top of their fields.
الذين وصلوا للقمة في مجالاتهم
And they need him in order to do their job.
والذين يحتاجونه لأداء وظائفهم
And a life that once seemed brief and insignificant
والحياة التي بدت يومًا مختصرة وتافهة
revealed itself to be vital, everlasting and relevant.
أظهرت أنها حيوية ومستمرة للأبد
And I only hope that my life can be as relevant.
وأتمنى فقط أن تكون حياتي وثيقة الصلة كهذه
Thank you.
شكرًا لكم.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)